<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<article>
  <articleinfo>
    <title>Map of the network connection</title>

    <subtitle>Port, Port manager</subtitle>

    <author>
      <firstname>Petr</firstname>

      <surname>Beran</surname>
    </author>
  </articleinfo>

  <section>
    <title>Role in the team</title>

    <para>In this project I was responsible for designing
    <code>portManager</code>, backend class which creates, deletes and
    validates ports between devices, as well as implementing this class's
    interface. I also implemented several GUI tweaks and created unit tests
    for <code>portManager</code>.</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Port</title>

    <para>Class that represents a connection between two devices. At this
    moment, <code>Port</code> does not have a <code>portType</code> property,
    which will be added later when wifi ports will be implemented.</para>

    <section>
      <title>Properties of the port class:</title>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para><code>deviceA</code> - First of two devices in port.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para><code>deviceB</code> - Second of two devices needed in
          port.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para><code>(portType)</code> - Wifi or Ethernet. Will be
          implemented later.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para><code>portType</code> will be the only property that can be
      changed and will be the only one with setter. Changing either
      <code>deviceA</code> or <code>deviceB</code> is not allowed and only
      getters of these properties are available.</para>

      <para>It is not allowed to have port without both devices. These devices
      have reference for the same port. First and second device must be
      different.</para>

      <para>Two ports are equal if their devices are same, no matter the
      order. There cannot be multiple ports between two same devices.</para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Port Manager</title>

    <para>Port manager is a class that allows basic operations over ports.
    Ports can be either created or deleted. While creating, port is also
    validated if there are no missing arguments. Updating a port is not
    implemented at this moment. Changing <code>portType</code> will be
    available later and changes of either device is not allowed. Deleting and
    creating new port is recommended instead of changing one or both devices
    in a port. When creating port from XML, imported ports are placed in the
    spot specified in the XML. This guarantees consistency of imported data.
    Ports created in application find first available spot in both devices, if
    there is one. Both methods also checks for duplicate ports between two
    devices.</para>
  </section>
</article>
