<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">

<article>
    <articleinfo>
        <title>Map of the network connection</title>
        <subtitle>
            Device, Device manager
        </subtitle>
        <author>
            <firstname>Kristýna</firstname>
            <surname>Leknerová</surname>
        </author>
    </articleinfo>

    <section>
        <title>Role in the team</title>
        <para>
		My role in the team was to design class <code>Device</code>, which holds every important property of the network device. I implemented <code>DeviceManager</code>, which ensures basic operations over devices - addition, removal, change and search by various parameters. I also modified file import and am responsible for showing the imported devices in GUI and file export.
        </para>
    </section>             
        
    <section>
        <title>Device</title>
        <para>
            Class that represents a single device. Constructed via the Builder pattern, which allows some modularity with respect to its optional parameters.
        </para>
	<section>
		<title>Properties of the device class:</title>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem><para><code>did</code> - Unique numerical identifier.</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para><code>deviceType</code> - Type of the device. See supported device types in the respective documentation.</para></listitem>
		<listitem><para><code>address</code> - Unique string identifier. Must be in valid MAC address format, ie. 01-02-03-04-aa-bb or 01:02:03:04:aa:bb.</para></listitem>
		<listitem><para><code>numberOfPorts</code> - maximal number of ports available to the device. Must be non-negative.</para></listitem>
		<listitem><para><code>arrayOfPorts</code> - List of ports of fixed size (<code>numberOfItems</code> size).</para></listitem>
		<listitem><para><code>name</code> - Name of the device.</para></listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
	</section>
	<para>
	<code>deviceType</code>, <code>numberOfPorts</code> and <code>name</code> properties can be changed. Changing <code>numberOfPorts</code> shrinks/enlarges current <code>arrayOfPorts</code>; shrinking crops reduntant port connections.
	</para>
	<para><code>arrayOfPorts</code> is list created as <code>Arrays.toList()</code> to ensure fixed size. This prevents to add or remove any port (and thus change the list size), but allows to get or set any list element.
	</para>
	<para>Two devices are equal if their <code>did</code> and <code>address</code> are equal.
	</para>
    </section>            
    
    <section>
        <title>Device Manager</title>
        <para>
            Device manager is a class that allows basic operations over devices. Devices can be created, updated and deleted. Using Java 8 streaming API, this class also allows search operations based on various conditions, most important being search by device <code>did</code> and <code>address</code>.
        </para>
    </section>                 
</article>